Matthew Kaus

matthewkausfox@gmail.com | 505-879-6014| linkedIn/matthewpkaus | github/MatthewKaus | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Web developer with data science experience educated at the University of New Mexico. I have recently earned a certificate in full-stack web development from the University of Arizona, with knowledge in JavaScript, CSS, and React. Excited to learn new technologies and to develop responsive and dynamic websites, with a clean and modern user experience.

SKILLS

Proficient in: JavaScript, Git, React, Node, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Heroku, MySQL, MongoDB **Familiar with, and interested in learning more about:** Python, C, C++, Svelte, Angular, Vue, AWS

Tools: Git, LaTeX, Slack, Zoom, GitHub

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

Tuscon, AR | Aug 2021

University of Arizona

After studying in college, I decided to take on the challenge of attend a coding boot-camp. In which I undertook a rigorous curriculum that included learning the SERN and MERN stack.

Liberal Arts Gallup, NM | Dec, 2020

University of New Mexico

With my enrollment in a dual credit high school, I was able to attend college to pursue my liberal arts. Given the opportunity to be part of the National Security Studies Program at UNM, stimulated my interest in computer science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TRILOGY EDUCATION | FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT (TA)

Remote | Apr 2022 - Present

- Mentor students with debugging assignments and projects, and encourage them in their journey through the Full Stack Curriculum.
- Assist students with online learning using tools including Zoom, Google Docs, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, and Git Bash.

WALMART | REMODEL (TEMPORARY)

Gallup, NM | Apr 2022 - June 2022

- Built relationships with customers to increase likelihood of repeat business.
- Self-sufficient and can work alone without being supervised.
- Appreciates problem-solving in group environments.

UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO | RESEARCH

Albuquerque, NM | Feb 2020 - May 2020

- Studied and utilized statistics, LaTeX, R Programming within a three month span for Data Science.
- Presented technical research during conferences.

PROJECTS

STOCK WATCHLIST ☑

JAVASCRIPT, DAISYUI, MONGODB, SVELTE, EXPRESSJS, GRAPHQL, CHARTJS

Stock Watchlist is a small application that allows users to look up a stock to find out the price, as well as the latest news.

- Worked independently through the process of the full stack project.
- Utilizes Svelte as the framework of choice for learning new technology and new methods of writing code.

BENEFACTOR [7]

HTML5, JAVASCRIPT, CSS3, MySQL, HANDLEBARS, EXPRESSJS

Benefactor is a gift giving service, that allows users to gift to friends, family, or to make a strangers day. Allowing users to make and share lists for future giving plans.

- Collaborated and contributed ideas through the process of the project.
- Created the wire frame as well as creative lead for the user interface.
- Outlined the database and requirements for the schemas.